>> Jem Young: 但互联网以信任为基础。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: But
the Internet runs on trust.
这是一个很奇怪的概念，作为人类，
And it's a really weird concept that,
collectively as humanity,
我们在政治和战争上存在分岐
we have our disagreements on politics and
war and
是最棒的，但是我们大家都说，哎，
the best type of burrito, but
we all collectively said, hey,
让我们商定一套标准，让我的电脑可以跟你的电脑说话。
let's agree on a set of standards that
my computer can talk to your computer.
这在人类的过程中是非常重要的。
And this is a really big deal
in the course of mankind.
而且我不是说网上最伟大的发明
And, no, I'm not saying the Internet's
the greatest invention in the course
人类的世界
of mankind.
但事实上我们可以有这些不同的想法
But the fact that we can have
these disparate ideas about
软件工程应该如何运作，编程语言最好
how software engineering should work,
what's the best programming language,
最好的操作系统是什么但我们都同意这一套标准
what's the best operating system, but
we all agree on this set of standards and
我们可以相互交流的协议是不可思议的
protocols that we can talk to
each other I think is incredible.
我觉得我们的合作是把我们从动物中分离出来的
I think our cooperation is one of
the things that separates us from animals,
就像动物不能集体合作到我们可以
like animals can't collectively
cooperate to the level that we can, and
这反映在互联网上
that's reflected in the Internet.
你能告诉我对我的工作充满激情吗
Can you tell I'm passionate
about what I do?
我所说的是人类和社会科学以及所有这些东西。
That I'm talking about humanity and
social sciences and all that things.
但是网络在这个信任系统上运行，它是一系列的协议
But the Internet runs on this trust
system, and it's a series of protocols
大家都坐下来同意 30 年前的事了
that everybody sat down to agree
to like 30 years ago or something.
他们说，哎，这就是我电脑跟你说话的方式。
They said, hey,
this is how my computer can talk to you.
这个协议叫做 IP ，就代表了
And that protocol is called IP,
and that just stands for
互联网协议非常容易记住
Internet Protocol,
pretty easy to remember.
你可能听到了 TCP/IP
You've probably heard TCP/IP.
TCP 是传输控制协议，我们将在第二个方面谈论这个问题。
TCP is Transmission Control Protocol,
we'll talk about that in a second.
但这只是一个集体的想法如果我给你发送一些数据
But it's just this collective idea that
if I send you some data it's well-formed
好吧我知道怎么接受这个数据
enough that you say, okay,
I know how to accept this data.
我知道怎么写，念，我知道怎么发给你
I know how to write it, read it, and
I know how to send it back to you to
让你知道我拿到了那是互联网协议
let you know that I got it,
that's the Internet Protocol.
你可能都熟悉的 IP 地址
IP address you're probably
all familiar with.
这是一组数字只代表一个地址
It's a set of numbers that
just denotes an address,
就像一个邮政地址一样
just like a postal address, same thing.
>> Jem Young: IPv4，这就是我成长的地方。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: IPv4,
that's the thing that I grew up with.
这只是一系列的数字，更短，还有等待，
That's just a series of numbers,
much shorter, there are, wait,
我想我的秘密笔记有了
I think I have it in my secret notes,
I do.
有 43 亿 IP 地址，当时人们是这样说的，
There are 4.3 billion IP addresses,
which at the time people were like,
就不会有更多的电脑了
there will never be more
computers than that.
我们已经过去了
We've already blown past that.
我们实际上已经耗尽了 IP 地址。
We've actually run out of IP addresses.
如果它给你一个关于互联网无所不在的想法，
So if it gives you an idea of
how ubiquitous the Internet is,
现在互联网上的设备已经超过 34 亿台，
there are over 3.4 billion devices
connected the Internet right now,
你仔细想想就太疯狂了
which is kind of wild
when you think about it.
但是，这再次说明了你在历史上的一个教训。
But again, this just shows you
a lesson in history to plan ahead.
他们认为 34 亿是足够的。
[LAUGH] They thought
3.4 billion was enough.
还不够我们跑出来了
It wasn't enough, we ran out.
所以他们发明了这个叫做 IPv6的东西。
So they invented this thing called IPv6.
IPv6 是这样的序列。
IPv6 is a series looks like this.
有更多的数字，等等，看，
There's bigger numbers and
there's, wait, see,
我的笔记有三百四十头狮子
I've got it in my notes, 340 decillion.
我都不知道我是否说对了
I don't even know if
I'm saying that right.
三十八到三十
3.4 to 10 to the 38.
这已经足够了。
That is hopefully enough.
[ LAUGH] 希望有足够的地址，我们很快就不会跑出来了。
[LAUGH] Hopefully enough addresses
that we won't run out anytime soon.
我们会看到未来会发生什么但你永远不会知道
We'll see what happens in the future,
though, you never know.
也许我们会去火星的时候我就死了
Maybe we'll go to Mars and
by that time I'll be dead and hopefully
没有人在看这门课，因为，如果是的话，我们这个世界还有更大的问题。
no one's watching this course because, if
so, we have bigger problems in the world.
但这些是 IP 地址。
But these are IP addresses.
所以他们是互联网协议使用的地址
So they're addresses that
are used by the Internet Protocol
彼此交谈，让你知道，嘿，我来了。
to kind of talk to each other,
just let you know, hey, here I am.
这就是怎么找我的
Here's how to get to me.
就像我说的，这都是在一个叫做 TCP的不同的协议上运行的。
Like I said, this all runs on
a different protocol called TCP.
大多数人听到 TCP over IP，或者 IP over TCP ，它只是一个协议和
And most of you heard TCP over IP, or
IP over TCP, it's just a protocol and
计算机如何能够相互对话的标准化。
a standardization of how
computers can talk to each other.
你也听到了 UDP的短语。
And you also hear the phrase UDP.
也许人们对 UDP 不太熟悉，因为它是
Probably people are a little less
familiar with UDP because it's
但你很可能每天都不使用它
used heavily but you probably
don't use it in your day to day.
有谁知道 TCP 和 UDP 之间的区别吗 ?
Does anybody know the difference
between TCP and UDP?
萨姆我看到你点头了
Sam, I see you nodding.
还有人想去吗
Anybody else want to take a crack?
有人吗
Anybody?
吉米
Jimmy.
>> 扬声器 2: TCP 必须为每个文件协商连接。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: TCP has to negotiate
the connection for each file.
UDP 能够协商连接和
UDP is capable of
negotiating a connection and
然后在与同一服务器通信时将连接打开。
then it leaves the connection open while
it's communicating with the same server.
一完成上传或下载第一个文件就行了，好的，
As soon as it finishes uploading or
downloading the first files it says, okay,
然后再下一次
and then next and then next.
所以它最小化了往返的次数，或者来回的对话，
So it minimizes the round trips, or
the back and forth conversation, that's
以便开始传输和继续传输文件。
needed in order to begin transferring and
continue transferring files.
>> Jem Young: 这就是正确的答案。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: That's exactly right,
great answer.
TCP 是无损的，它保证
TCP it's lossless, it's guaranteed that
如果我给你寄一些关于 TCP 的信息
if I send you some information
over TCP it's going to make it.
它有一个叫做纠错，错误检查的东西。
It has things called error correction,
error checking.
UDP 和我说的不同
UDP is different where I just say, hey,
我想你也听到了我不在乎你是否不知道那是 UDP
and I assume you heard me and I don't
care if you didn't, and that's UDP.
基本上，这只是一个单向的信息爆炸。
Essentially, it's just
a one-way blast of information.
你可以看到为什么 UDP 的速度比 TCP 快，因为 TCP 必须说，嘿，你在吗 ?
And you can see why UDP is faster than TCP
because TCP has to say, hey, you there?
这叫做 SYN 包， S-Y-N 。
And that's called a SYN packet, S-Y-N.
然后客户回答，是的，我在这里有一个 ACK。
And then the client responds like,
yeah, I'm here with an ACK.
所以它发送了一个 ACK 包。
So it sends an ACK package.
你不需要知道这些东西但就像那个书呆子
You don't need to know this stuff, but
it's just like that nerd level trivia that
我我想让你下次出门时在酒吧里看起来很酷
I, I wanna make you look cool at
the bar next time you're hanging out.
你就像是某种东西的 TCP 和 IP 信息包之类的
You're like, yeah, something's TCP and
IP packets, things like that.
但它会谈判这一联系。
But it negotiates this connection.
所以它是 SYN ，然后是 SYN-ACK ，然后发送 ACK，
So it says SYN and then it says SYN-ACK,
and then it sends ACK, and
然后开始传输数据。
then you start transferring data.
所以在任何数据之前就已经有 4 个或 5 个连接
So there's already four or
five connections before any data is
甚至是发送和 UDP ，就是，哎，你明白吗 ?
even really sent versus UDP which is just,
hey, did you get it?
你拿到了吗 你拿到了吗
Did you get it?
别在意了
Don't care.
我只是给你发数据
I'm just sending you data.
事实上，我有一个关于 UDP 的好笑话，但你可能不明白。
And actually I have a good joke
about UDP but you might not get it.
>> 演讲者 3: 只是说说而已。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Just say it, though.
>> Jem Young: 不，这就是玩笑。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: No, that was the joke.
看见了吗
See?
>> 演讲者 3: [LAUGH] >> Jem Young:
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: [LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Thank you,
谢谢你在房间的后面
thank you person in the back of the room.
那是马克
That was Mark.
对你是个怪人笑话
Yeah, that was some nerd jokes for you.
所以，让我们尝试练习，让我们试试 ping。
So let's try an exercise, let's try ping.
Ping 是一个非常简短的请求。
Ping is a really short request.
上面写着，嘿，嘿，嘿，这就是它的全部。
It just says, hey, hey, hey,
hey, that's all it does.
所以，让我们在 twitter.com 和您的终端上，让我来做这个。
So let's go in ping twitter.com and into
your terminal, so I'm gonna do that here.
请登录 twitter.com。
Say ping twitter.com.
嘿它在那儿它还活着
Hey, it's there, it's alive.
杀死它只是 Ctrl+C 。
And to kill it we just Ctrl+C.
杀死任何东西的方法， Ctrl+C 。
Way to kill anything, Ctrl+C.
所以大家都成功了我想如果你在网上看我
So everybody successfully, I assume if
you're watching me on the Internet your
互联网工程和您成功地 ping 通了 twitter.com。
Internet works and
you successfully pinged twitter.com.
这一切都是说你在吗
And all this is saying is,
hey, are you there?
在吗 ?
Are you there?
所以我来了我来了我来了
And so like, yeah, I'm here,
I'm here, I'm here.
Ping 可用于调试站点。
Ping is useful for debugging your site.
如果你想说我的客户说连接的速度太慢了
If you're saying, man, my clients
are saying the connection's really slow.
最便宜的最简单的方法是让我的站点启动并运行吗 ?
What's the cheapest, easiest way to
find out is my site up and running?
那往返时间是多久
And how long's that round trip time?
所以来回是我发包的时候
So the round trip refers to
when I send the packet out and
它会回来我们只是在测量
it comes back, and
we're just measuring that.
另外一个措施是，好，我再谈几个希望。
Another thing it measures is, well,
I'll talk about hops in a second.
我来谈谈跳跳和跟踪路线
I'll talk about hops and trace route.
但平平只是一个不错的实用程序能在你的背兜里说
But ping is just a nice utility to have
in your back pocket just to say like,
哎，站起来了吗 ?
hey, is the site up?
太棒了
Yeah, cool.